

SARVATH S

DevOps Engineer

@ sarvathbabu@gmail.com

J +91 8870593339

Chennai, India

in www.linkedin.com/in/sarvath-s-1686421b6

SKILLS

CI-CD

AWS

Docker

Kubernetes

Jenkins

Shell scripting

Apache Airflow

Git

GitHub Actions

GitLab

Jira

Reactjs

Recoil

PROJECTS

- Judo Feb'23 to till date
- N-Next May'22 to Jan'23
- ICAPP Feb'21 to Apr'22
- ANB Sep'19 to Oct'20

CERTIFICATION

• Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)

EDUCATION

BE - CSE
 St Joseph's College Of Engineering
 Jul 2015 - Apr 2019

SUMMARY

Overall 4.5 years of experience, including 3.5 years specializing in DevOps, AWS Cloud Platform and 1 year as a ReactJs Developer. Proficient in some AWS services, CI/CD pipelines, Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes and Shell Scripting and possesses sound knowledge in Ansible.

EXPERIENCE

Software Analyst | Zeptoh Solutions Pvt Ltd.

FEB 2021 - Present

Chennai, India

- Implemented CI/CD pipelines, automating build, test, and deployment processes using Git, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Docker, AWS, Shell Scripting.
- Monitored and maintained system health, addressing incidents promptly to minimize downtime and enhance system reliability.
- Created and configured multiple EC2 instances for different teams and managed AWS service such as S3 for file management and created policies to secure S3 buckets
- Utilized Git for branching, tagging, and version management and managed Docker private repositories.
- Integrated GitHub Webhooks with Jenkins to automate software build and deployment processes using Jenkins Pipeline.
- Developed UI components using ReactJs and Ant Design (Antd) library; optimized
 application performance to improve load times and participated in on-call rotations
 and incident response, ensuring timely resolution of development mode issues.
- Utilized Jira for issue reporting, status updates, and activity reporting.
- Demonstrated POC for deploying applications across multiple servers using Ansible playbooks.
- Involved in data analysis activity using Python Library Pandas
- Monitored EC2 disk and CPU utilization by creating alarm based on threshold limit using CloudWatch and triggering notification using SNS.
- Built CI/CD pipeline on AWS by using CodeCommit, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, Code-Pipeline.
- Managed workflows using Apache Airflow in Contract Lifecycle management application.

Trainee Cloud Engineer | Precision Infomatic Pvt Ltd.

Sep 2019 - Oct 2020

Chennai, India

- Interacted with clients to track the requirements.
- Had the chance to work with Linux and Windows team and worked on basic tasks such as monitoring security patches, shell scripting, creating S3 buckets, configuring AWS EC2 instances.
- Automated the shutdown of AWS EC2 instances during non-business hours.
- Creating and updating issue in Jira and Itop to track the incidents.